[
  {
    "question": "What metrix are used to construct decision trees?",
    "answer": "ID3, C4.5, CART or Gini impurity"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we classify a new data instance",
    "answer": "we start at the root and make decisions at each node based on the instance's features until we reach a leaf node, which gives us the classification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the Deterministic Model:",
    "answer": "an equation or set of equations that allow us to fully determine the value of the dependent variable from the values of the independent variables"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the Probabilistic Model:",
    "answer": "a method used to make predictions but the predictions will be approximate due to the randomness of a real world process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is supervised Learning:",
    "answer": "Supervised learning is a type of machine learning where the algorithm is trained on a dataset that includes the input data and the correct outputs. This training helps the algorithm make predictions on new, unseen data"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the goal of supervised Learning:",
    "answer": "The goal of supervised Learning is to learn a mapping from inputs to outputs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some examples of supervised Learning:",
    "answer": "Regression and classification tasks like predicting house prices or identifying spam emails are some examples of supervised Learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "When would we use supervised Learning:",
    "answer": "Supervised Learning is used when the relationship between input data and the output label is crucial, and labeled data is available"
  },
  {
    "question": "When is Supervised learning Ideal?:",
    "answer": "Supervised learning is ideal for prediction and classification tasks"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Unsupervised Learning:",
    "answer": "unsupervised learning involves learning patterns from unlabeled data"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the goal of Unsupervised Learning:",
    "answer": "The goal of unsupervised learning is for the algorithm to discover patterns and structures in data on its own without being given any specific outputs or labels to guide it"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some examples of Unsupervised Learning:",
    "answer": "Clustering, dimensionality reduction, and association rule learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some examples of association rule learning:",
    "answer": "Feature reduction, customer segmentation  and market basket analysis are examples of association rule learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "When would we use unsupervised Learning:",
    "answer": "Unsupervised learning is best for data exploration and pattern discovery. When the goal is to understand and explore data, uncover hidden patterns, or identify clusters."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the basic difference between Supervised and Unsupervised learning ?",
    "answer": "The primary goal of supervised learning is typically to make predictions. Where as unsupervised learning aims to explore the underlying structure of the data."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does CRISP-DM stand for:",
    "answer": "Cross Industry Standard Process for Data Mining."
  },
  {
    "question": "Outline the 6 steps in the CRISP-DM model",
    "answer": "Business Understanding, Data Understanding, Data Preparation, Modeling, Evaluation, Deployment "
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the first 3 steps in CRISP-DM model again",
    "answer": "Business Understanding, Data Understanding, Data Preparation "
  },
  {
    "question": "Name thelast 3 steps in CRISP-DM model again",
    "answer": "Modeling, Evaluation, Deployment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Business Understanding step:",
    "answer": "Business Understanding involves defining the problem, determining its relevance to business goals, and translating it into a data mining context"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Data Understanding step:",
    "answer": "Collect data. get familiar with the data. Identify data quality issues. detect interesting subsets for further examination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Data Preparation step:",
    "answer": "Data Preparation entails transforming raw data into a suitable dataset for analysis, involving cleaning, selecting, and feature engineering"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Modelling step:",
    "answer": "Modelling involves selecting and configuring machine learning algorithms, such as Decision Trees, to fit the prepared data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Evaluation step:",
    "answer": "Evaluate the model before deployment. Often another iteration is required, going back to the Business Understanding Phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "Detail the Deployment step:",
    "answer": "Plan and execute the deployment of the model. Produce final reports, conduct a final review, and prepare for ongoing support and maintenance."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the CRISP-DM model emphasize?",
    "answer": "the cyclical nature of data mining projects, where the outcomes of each stage can impact previous steps, requiring iteration and refinement"
  },
  {
    "question": "When are some of the negatives of the CRISP-DM model",
    "answer": "Some negatives of the CRISP-DM model include its unpredictability due to its exploratory nature, the potential need for multiple prototypes  and the risk of costly mistakes if a solution is engineered and deployed prematurely."
  },
  {
    "question": "When is it best to use the CRISP-DM model",
    "answer": "The CRISP-DM model is flexible and can be adapted to fit a wide range of data mining projects"
  },
    {
      "question": "Linear Regression is a foundational concept in machine learning, often used for Predicting what?",
      "answer": "quantitative response"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a quantitative response in machine learning?",
      "answer": "quantitative response in machine learning is a numerical output that a model predicts such as the price of something"
    },
    {
      "question": "What relationship is linear regression based on?",
      "answer": "linear regression is based on the relationship between the dependent variable and one or more independent variables"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a dependent variable?",
      "answer": "a dependent variable is what we want to predict"
    },
    {
      "question": "Give an example of the dependent variable in a housing price prediction model",
      "answer": "The house price would be the dependent variable"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an independent variable?",
      "answer": "independent variable is what we are using to predict"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are some examples of independant variables?",
      "answer": "location size and age would be examples of independent variables"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the linear equation formula?",
      "answer": "y equals mx plus c"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Y in the formula represent?",
      "answer": "The Dependent variable or what we want to predict"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the X in the formula represent?",
      "answer": "the independent variable or what we used to predict"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the M in the formula represent?",
      "answer": "The slope of the line"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the C in the formula represent?",
      "answer": "The Y intercept"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do we find the Find the Parameters a and b",
      "answer": "To find parameters a and b, we analyze existing x and y data to estimate these parameters, essentially determining the line of best fit through the data points"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the goal of linear regression?",
      "answer": "The goal of linear regression is to model the linear relationship between a dependent variable and one or more independent variables"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the basic steps in the process we would use to get the linear regression prediction",
      "answer": "data collection model training and prediction"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of the Data Colection step when trying to predict the price of a house based on its size",
      "answer": "gather data on various houses including their sizes and selling prices"
    },
    {
      "question": "Give an example of the model training step in the process",
      "answer": "Using the data we train our linear regression model by finding the most suitable values for mx + c that best fit the data"
    },
    {
      "question": "Outline the prediction step",
      "answer": "Once the model is trained we can use it to predict the price of a house of any given size"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would we evaluate how well the model fits the data?",
      "answer": "often using metrics like Mean Squared Error"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do we need to do to find the Line of Best fit",
      "answer": "Minimize the sum of the squares of the errors"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do we find the Line of Best fit",
      "answer": "this is usually done using a method called least squares"
    },
    {
      "question": "The least squares method is a statistical technique used in linear regression to find the line that best fits the data. Explain how it works",
      "answer": "The least squares method minimizes the sum of squared differences between observed values and those predicted by the regression line, effectively finding the best fit line for the data."
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the least squares method produce?",
      "answer": "a straight line that minimizes the sum of the squares of the errors."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do we make Predictions with Linear Regression?",
      "answer": "Once we have the line of best fit we can use it to make predictions"
    },
    {
      "question": "using the house example if B0 = 50,000 and B1 = 300 price per square foot what would the prediction for the price of a 2000 square foot house be?",
      "answer": "price equals 50,000 plus 300 multiplied by two thousand equals 650,000"
    },
    {
      "question": "Give some examples of real world senarios were Linear regression is widly used",
      "answer": "Linear regression is widely used in economics business biology engineering and many other fields"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another name/ meaning of 'Residuals'?",
      "answer": "Errors"
    },
    {
      "question": "Give an example of a residual",
      "answer": "differences between predicted value of y and actual value of y"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is wrong with trying to minimize sum of the errors when finding the line of best fit?",
      "answer": "positive and negative errors will cancel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is linear regression a starting point for?",
      "answer": "It is a starting point for understanding relationships between variables and making predictions based on these relationships"
    },
    {
      "question": "When does linear regression works best?",
      "answer": "Linear regression works best when the data has a linear relationship"
    },
    {
      "question": "When is linear regression an unsuitable model?",
      "answer": "If the relationship in the data isn't linear"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a 'cost function' or 'objective function' in linear regression",
      "answer": "an opimization problem"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is an opimization problem is normally solved",
      "answer": "An opimization problem is normally solved by determining values that minimize or maximize an objective function"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the objective/cost function in simple linear regression?",
      "answer": "the sum of the squares of the errors"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the abbrievated version ofthe sum of the squares of the errors?",
      "answer": "S S E"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why is Simple Linear Regression called 'Simple'?",
      "answer": "because there is only one independent variable"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a Coefficient in machine learning?",
      "answer": "a coefficient is a numerical value associated with a variable in a model, representing the strength and direction of the relationship between that feature and the target variable"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a common mehod used when Estimatings the Coefficients",
      "answer": "The least squares method produces a straight line that minimizes the sum of the squares of the errors"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the  Conditions Necessary for Linear Regression Analysis?",
      "answer": "The probability distribution of errors is normal. The mean of the errors is 0. The standard deviation of the errors is a constant regardless of the value of x. The value of the error associated with any particular value of y is independent of the error associated with any other value of y"
    },
    {
      "question": "How might Residual Analysis show Linear Regression may not be optimal for a regression problem",
      "answer": "If the residuals show a pattern when plotted against the predicted values or a feature, it suggests that the relationship is not linear. Ideally, residuals should be randomly scattered around zero with no discernible pattern"
    },
    {
      "question": "How might Poor Fit on Non-linear Data determine that Linear Regression may not be optimal for a regression problem",
      "answer": "Linear Regression assumes a linear relationship between variables. If the actual relationship is non-linear, the model will have poor predictive accuracy. Plotting the observed data and the predicted line can visually demonstrate this poor fit"
    }
]